{
    "id": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
    "name": "Welding: Part B",
    "topicId": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
    "questions": [
        {
            "id": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "topicId": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "question": "Which gas is produced using the air liquefaction process?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "acetylene",
                "oxygen",
                "propane",
                "MAPP"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["oxygen"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "topicId": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "question": "What should be done before the cylinder valve protective caps are removed?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Cylinders should be pressure-tested.",
                "Cylinders should be secured.",
                "Cylinder valves should be cracked.",
                "Regulators should be installed."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Cylinders should be secured."],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "topicId": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "question": "To protect the regulator gauges from being damaged:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "only use regulators with a pre-set stage.",
                "release the adjusting screw before you open the cylinder valve.",
                "engage the adjusting screw to allow unrestricted gas flow.",
                "use only gauges equipped with stainless steel bourdon tubes."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["release the adjusting screw before you open the cylinder valve."],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "topicId": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "question": "When a piece of metal is cut, it creates a cut gap called the:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "preheater",
                "bead",
                "kerf",
                "crater"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["kerf"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "topicId": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "question": "On a combination cutting torch, the oxygen valve on the torch handle must be:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "closed tightly.",
                "partially open.",
                "fully open.",
                "there is no oxygen valve on the torch handle."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["fully open."],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "topicId": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "question": "When the cut is rough and slag accumulates on the bottom edge, what is the likely cause?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "using propane fuel gas",
                "using oxygen that is only 99.5% pure",
                "using a dirty tip",
                "using acetylene that is only 50% pure"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["using a dirty tip"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "topicId": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "question": "When piercing holes in a plate you should:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "press the cutting lever sharply to start the cut.",
                "allow the preheat cone to touch the material surface.",
                "raise the oxygen pressure by 25%.",
                "raise the tip when the cutting lever is depressed."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["raise the tip when the cutting lever is depressed."],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "topicId": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "question": "What is the likely problem if the kerf edges are melting back together behind the cut?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "The tip is too large for the material thickness.",
                "Impurities are present in the fuel gas.",
                "The carbon content of the steel is too low.",
                "Oxygen purity is too high."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["The tip is too large for the material thickness."],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "topicId": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "question": "You can determine a good quality cut by:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "inspecting the kerf lines.",
                "asking the foreman.",
                "the amount of cutting experience the operator has.",
                "the amount of oxygen and acetylene consumed."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["inspecting the kerf lines."],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "topicId": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "question": "Kerf draglines on a properly performed shape cut should be:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "irregular in profile.",
                "curved to match the shape.",
                "perpendicular to the plate surface.",
                "horizontally inclined."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["perpendicular to the plate surface."],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "topicId": "5a602c2e-0e82-4320-87c0-78f0c1102c32",
            "question": "If you notice the preheat flames changing from neutral to carbonizing during the cutting process, the most likely cause would be that the:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "oxygen cylinder is nearly empty.",
                "acetylene consumption is too high.",
                "acetylene cylinder is nearly empty.",
                "tip is dirty and requires cleaning."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["oxygen cylinder is nearly empty."],
            "explanation": ""
        }
    ]
}

